Guide to the Theatre Survey Records, 1963-1980 CTC.1977.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Theatre Survey Records
1963-1980
1973-1979
ULS Archives & Special Collections
American Society for Theatre Research
CTC.1977.01
9.25 Linear Feet
Theatre Survey, the official journal of the American Society for Theater Research (ASTR), began publication as an annual journal in 1960. The journal was edited first at Brandeis, then for a few years at Princeton, before it came to the University of Pittsburgh in 1963. The collection is arranged chronologically, and the records include general correspondence, financial records, edited typescripts of published articles with related correspondence, miscellaneous items, and a small amount of ASTR material, most of which is related to subscriptions.
Related Material
See also Curtis Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Information Files and the periodicals ASTR Newsletter, Membership Directories, and Miscellany.
Acquisition Information
Materials were transferred from the University of Pittsburgh Theatre Arts Department to the Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theater Collection in 1977 and 1981.
History
Theatre Survey, the official journal of the American Society for Theater Research, began publication as an annual in 1960. Originally supported by a Brandeis University grant, it was first edited at Brandeis, and for a few years, at Princeton. Beginning in 1963, Theatre Survey, was supported by the University of Pittsburgh and starting with Volume 5, 1964, when it became a semi-annual publication, it was also edited here. Pitt editors included Ralph G. Allen, George E. Bogusch, Attilio Favorini, and Raymond Pentzell. Dr. Favorini has been Executive Editor from 1972.
Editorship of Theatre Survey was transferred from the University of Pittsburgh to State University of New York, Albany campus beginning with Volume 21 in 1980.
Scope and Content Notes
Arranged chronologically, the records include general correspondence, financial records, edited typescripts of published articles with related correspondence, etc., and also a small amount of ASTR material, most of which is related to subscriptions. The records are not complete. The records include edited typescripts and related correspondence arranged by volume and issue, miscellaneous correspondence, and ASTR related materials. Miscellaneous financial records, including invoices, subscription records, etc. are in a separate chronological series. The records comprise all those extant from the University of Pittsburgh's sponsorship of Theatre Survey, 1963-1976.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Theatre Survey Records, 1963-1980, CTC.1977.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Theatre Survey Records, 1963-1980, CTC.04, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Mailing lists; Financial records; Correspondence; Theater -- United States -- Periodicals; Theatrers -- Stage-setting and scenery; Performing arts -- United States; Theater -- United States; Theatre survey; Theater; Periodicals; Invoices; Subscription lists; Transcripts; Articles; State University of New York at Albany; University of Pittsburgh; American Society for Theatre Research; Princeton University; Brandeis University; Shakespeare, William; Favorini, Attilio, 1943-; Allen, Ralph G.; Shakespeare, William; Shakespeare, William
- General correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Mailing lists, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Financial records, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- David Gild article - vol. V, no. 1, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Frederick J. Hunter article - vol. V, no. 1, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Covers - vol. V, no. 1, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- American Society for Theater Research, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- General correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mailing lists, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence - vol. VI, no. 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- M. Ray Adams correspondence - vol. VI, no. 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Kalman Burnim correspondence - vol. VI, no. 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- James H. Butler correspondence - vol. VI, no. 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Stanly T. Lewis correspondence - vol. VI, no. 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Douglas McDermott correspondence - vol. VI, no. 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence - vol. VI, no. 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Ned A. Bowman article - vol. VI, no. 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Edward A. Langhans article - vol. VI, no. 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Calvin L. Pritner article - vol. VI, no. 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Pat M. Ryan article - vol. VI, no. 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Ronald E. Sherriffs article - vol. VI, no. 2, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- American Society for Theater Research, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Financial records, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Richard E. Amacher correspondence - vol. VII, no. 2, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Douglas McDermott correspondence - vol. VII, no. 2, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Arthur H. Saxon correspondence - vol. VII, no. 2, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- William S.E. Coleman article - vol. VIII, no. 1, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Gresdna Doty correspondence - vol. VIII, no. 1, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Leonard H. Knight article - vol. VIII, no. 1, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Terence Tobin correspondence - vol. VIII, no. 1, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Eugene K. Bristow and William R. Reardon article and related correspondence - vol. VIII, no. 2, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Donald C. Mullin article - vol. VIII, no. 2, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Richard Stoddard article - vol. VIII, no. 2, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Frank W. Wadsworth article - vol. VIII, no. 2, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- American Society for Theater Research, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- General correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Vol. IX, no. 1, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Robert J. Green article - vol. IX, no. 1, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Francis Hodge article - vol. IX, no. 1, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- John Ripley article - vol. IX, no. 1, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Marvin Rosenberg article - vol. IX, no. 1, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Financial records, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- General correspondence, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Vol. X, no. 1, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Betty Bandel article - vol. X, no. 1, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Robert Cohen article - vol. X, no. 1, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Robert B. Montilla article - vol. X, no. 1, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Raymond J. Pentzell article - vol. X, no. 1, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- James H. Butler article - vol. X, no. 2, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Lawrence P. Goodman article - vol. X, no. 2, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Paul S. Hostetler article - vol. X, no. 2, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Frank W. Wadsworth article - vol. X, no. 2, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Albert Wertheim article - vol. X, no. 2, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- General correspondence, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Financial records, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Vol. XI, no. 1, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Sidney P. Albert article - vol. XI, no. 1, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Marvin Carlson article - vol. XI, no. 1, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Philip H. Highfill article - vol. XI, no. 1, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- G. M. Pinciss article - vol. XI, no. 1, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Donald C. Mullin article - vol. XI, no. 2, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Christopher Murray article - vol. XI, no. 2, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Merrill A. Rosenberg article - vol. XI, no. 2, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Frank W. Wadsworth article - vol. XI, no. 2, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- General correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Financial records, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Richard Hosley article - vol. XII, no. 1, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Frederick E. Snyder article - vol. XII, no. 1, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Richard Stoddard article - vol. XII, no. 1, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Alan Woods article - vol. XII, no. 1, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Ryder Hector Currie article - vol. XII, no. 2, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Alan S. Downer article - vol. XII, no. 2, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Bamber Gascoigne correspondence - vol. XII, no. 2, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- John Harrop article - vol. XII, no. 2, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Leonard Powlick article - vol. XII, no. 2, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- John W. Robinson note - vol. XII, no. 2, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- A. Richard Sogliuzzo article - vol. XII, no. 2, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- General correspondence, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Financial records, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Richard L. DeMolen article - vol. XIII, no. 1, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Robert Fahrner article - vol. XIII, no. 1, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- James M. Leonard article - vol. XIII, no. 1, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Malcolm Morley article - vol. XIII, no. 1, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Raymond J. Pentzell note - vol. XIII, no. 1, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Alan Woods – Ryder Hector Currie debate - vol. XIII, no. 1, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Max Reinhardt's Theaters. Walther R. Volbach article - special issue, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Walter R. Volbach correspondence - special issue, 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Julia Curtis note - vol. XIII, no. 2, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Billy J. Harbin article - vol. XIII, no. 2, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Barnard Hewitt correspondence - vol. XIII, no. 2, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Edward A. Langhans article - vol. XIII, no. 2, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- David Rinear article - vol. XIII, no. 2, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Michael Shapiro article - vol. XIII, no. 2, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Richard Stoddard note - vol. XIII, no. 2, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- American Society for Theater Research, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- General correspondence, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Financial records, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Financial records, paid invoices, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Financial records, unpaid invoices, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Vol. XIV, no. 2, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Lawrence M. Clopper article - vol. XIV, no. 2, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Patricia W. O'Conner article - vol. XIV, no. 2, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Richard Sogliuzzo article - vol. XIV, no. 2, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Mary del Villar note - vol. XIV, no. 2, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Don B. Wilmuth article - vol. XIV, no. 2, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- American Society for Theater Research, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- General correspondence, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Financial records, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- American Society for Theater Research, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- General correspondence, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- American Society for Theater Research, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- American Society for Theater Research, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- George B. Bryan article - vol. XV, no. 2, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Terry Oggel article - vol. XIV, no. 1, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Edward C. Powers article - vol. XV, no. 2, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- S. Viswanathan article - vol. XV, no. 2, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Barry Daniels article - vol. XVI, no. 1, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Roger Herzel article - vol. XVI, no. 1, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Albert E. Kalson article - vol. XVI, no. 1, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Diane B. Marlone article - vol. XVI, no. 1, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Jack W. McCullough article - vol. XVI, no. 2, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Michael R. Booth - vol. XVII, no. 1, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Correspondence regarding entire issue - vol. XVII, no. 1, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Carole J. Carlisle article -vol. XVII, no. 1, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Selma Jeanne Cohen article - vol. XVII, no. 1, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Phyliss Dircks - vol. XVII, no. 1, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- John Bush Jones article - vol. XVII, no. 1, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Cecil Price article - vol. XVII, no. 1, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Harry M. Ritchie - vol. XVII, no. 1, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- A. H. Saxon - vol. XVII, no. 1, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Davidson and Mason article - vol. XVII, no. 2, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Anthony Graham-White article - vol. XVII, no. 2, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Lynn Hiams article - vol. XVII, no. 2, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Judith Milhous article - vol. XVII, no. 2, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Edward M. Moore article - vol. XVII, no. 2, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Michael Mullin article - vol. XVII, no. 2, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Ronald J. Palumbo article - vol. XVII, no. 2, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Richard J. Cox article - vol. XVIII, no. 1, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- John R. Wolcott article - vol. XVIII, no. 1, 1974-1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Briant Hamor Lee article - vol. XVIII, no. 2, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Raymond D. Shady - vol. XVIII, no. 2, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- James F. Stottlar article - vol. XVIII, no. 2, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Gary Jay Williams correspondence - vol. XVIII, no. 2, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Gerald M Berkowitz article - vol. XIX, no. 1, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Douglas McDermott article - vol. XIX, no. 1, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Linda Suny Myrsiades article - vol. XIX, no. 1, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Laurence Senelick article - vol. XIX, no. 1, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Leonie Star article - vol. XIX, no. 1, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Book reviews and correspondence - vol. XIX, no. 1, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- James and Joseph Donohue article - vol. XIX, no. 2, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Robert Fahrner article - vol. XIX, no. 2, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Oliver W. Ferguson article - vol. XIX, no. 2, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Shirley Strum Kenny - vol. XIX, no. 2, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Orville K. Larson article - vol. XIX, no. 2, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Milhouse and Hume article - vol. XIX, no. 2, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Bruce Podewell article - vol. XIX, no. 2, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Joseph R. Roach article - vol. XIX, no. 2, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Colin Visser article - vol. XIX, no. 2, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Book reviews and correspondence - vol. XIX, no. 2, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Heinrich Falk article ff1 - vol. XX, no. 1, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Heinrich Falk article ff2 - vol. XX, no. 1, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- William Kleb article - vol. XX, no. 1, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Bruce A. McConachie article - vol. XX, no. 1, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Tice L. Miller article - vol. XX, no. 1, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Wayne H. Phelps article - vol. XX, no. 1, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- John Orrell article - vol. XX, no. 1, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Laurence Senelick article - vol. XX, no. 1, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Wilson F. Engel article - vol. XX, no. 2, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Levi Phillips - vol. XX, no. 2, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- James S. Moy article - vol. XX, no. 2, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- David D. Mays article - vol. XX, no. 2, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Alvin Goldfarb article - vol. XX, no. 2, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Daniel Barrett article - vol. XX, no. 2, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Typescript index volumes 1-20 - vol. XX, no. 2 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Typescript author - title index - vol. XX, no. 2 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Rejected articles, 1972-1978 (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
- Rejected articles, 1977-1979 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
- Book reviews and correspondence (Box 13, Folder 3)
- General correspondence, 1971-1980 (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
- Editorial correspondence, 1969-1979 (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
- Correspondence regarding Ned Bourman's candidacy for Executive communication, 1970-1972 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous research proposals: CIC holdings, Charles MacArthur Center for the American Theater – London Stage 1800-1900, 1975-1977 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Copyright files and related correspondence, 1964-1974 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- MLA abstracts and related correspondence (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Subscription information, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Xerox microfilm agreement, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Exchange with other publications, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Annual reports, 1970-1977 (Box 15, Folder 1-8)
- Executive committee minutes, 1973-1977 (Box 15, Folder 9-13)
- Expense analysis and documentation – executive committee, 1964-1970 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Executive committee interim financial reports, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Executive committee, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 16-17)
- Publication committee and related correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box 15, Folder 18)
- ASTR miscellaneous membership forms (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
- ASTR reforms, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Unpaid invoices, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Paid invoices, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 2-5)
- Renewals, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Paid invoices, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
- Renewals, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Paid invoices, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
- Renewals, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Paid invoices, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
- Renewals, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Paid invoices, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 5-6)
- Paid invoices, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
- Unpaid and cancelled invoices, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Renewals, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Paid invoices, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 1-3)
- Unpaid invoices, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Early agreements University of Pittsburgh Press etcetera, 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Bids, 1963-1967 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Correspondence with publishers, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Cancelled invoices, 1973-1978 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Printing and mailing requisitions and purchase orders, 1973-1980 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Account printouts, 1974-1976 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Disbursements - financial, 1975-1980 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Claims – invoices – miscellaneous correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Tab runs – computer print-outs, 1976-1980 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Cash reports, 1976-1980 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Claims and complaints - financial, 1976-1980 (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
- Subscription agencies, 1978-1980 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Forms – to subscriber invoice (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Photographs (Box 24, Folder 7)